Divakar Kumar

Email: dvkr22@gmail.com Mobile: +91 9380960568 Portfolio: - https://divakark22.github.io/

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/divakar-kumar-5419b7172/

Github :- https://github.com/DivakarK22

SUMMERY

Overall 3.5+ years of experience in IT industry and relevant 2+ years in DevOps Engineer in supporting, automating, and optimizing mission critical deployments in Baremetal & cloud, leveraging configuration management, CI/CD and DevOps processes. Implementing cloud strategy in various environments.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Dev/ops Tools: Jenkins, Ansible, Docker, GIT, Salt, Python

Monitoring tools: Sensu, Prometheus and Grafana.

Cloud: AWS

Web Server : TOMCAT

Protocols : TCP/IP, SSH, HTTP, HTTPS,

OS Platform : Linux, Ubuntu, Windows ,MacOS

EDUCATION

Vels College Chennai, Tamil Nadu

Bachelor of Information Tech (BSC.IT) 2016 – 2019

Jaigopal Garodia National H.S.S Chennai, Tamil Nadu

HSC (Higher Secondary Certificate) 2014 – 2016

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Double Negative (DNEG) :Sep 2021 – Present
Sutherland Global Services :Jun 2020 - Jun 2021
Comodo Cybersecurity :May 2019 – Jun 2020

Double Negative (DNEG)

Module : CI/CD, AWS Role : Tech Jr

Scope & Overview:

Work involves the end-to-end Application deployment using CI/CD pipelines, provisioning and maintenance of cloud Infrastructure on the AWS cloud through Change Requests, Tickets, Incidents and Project.

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Responsible for Continuous Integration and Deployment of the application using Jenkins CI/CD pipelines.
- Actively manage, improve, and monitor infrastructure on Baremetal VM's using Grafana, Prometheus and Sensu.
- Designed and implemented centralized logging and monitoring system using Grafana and Prometheus

- Troubleshooting the issues in the CI/CD pipelines, analyzing and comparing the build scripts with unit builds to make the deployment successful.
- Worked on GIT push and pull operations, Branching strategy of the application development and maintenance of the GIT and Jenkins integrations.
- Used Ansible for Configuration Management and having good knowledge of writing Playbooks.
- Automated build and deployment using Jenkins to reduce human error and speed up production processes.
- Working on the development project for automating the build workflows using Saltsack for building the Infrastructure.

Sutherland Global Services

Scope & Overview:

Designed and implemented a fully automated CI/CD pipeline using Jenkins, Git, and Ansible which reduced deployment time by 50%

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Deployed and managed various applications and services on Baremetal Virtual Machines(Linux/Windows/MacOS).
- Implemented automated deployment using Ansible and Git on multiple environments
- Configured and maintained monitoring and alerting using Grafana and Sensu
- Designed and implemented Infrastructure as Code (IaC) using Saltstack
- Developed and maintained scripts using PowerShell/Shell Scripting for automation and administration tasks
- Handling L1 and L2 level issues, involved in the client calls, done several deployments, resolving the tickets to ensure system availability as per multiple Service Level Agreements (SLA).
- Administrated and Implemented CI tools Jenkins for automated builds.
- Worked on Version control system with GIT and Build and deployed the Code into production.
- Worked on Apache and Tomcat web servers to run the Applications.

Comodo Cybersecurity

Scope & Overview:

Provided technical support to the development team for infrastructure-related issues

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Resposible for hosting servers, account creation and service critical issues
- Took ownership of escalated issue for CentOS/Apache webhosting servers, Provided support for priority issues escalated from social media.
- Handled all SSL related configurations.
- Supporting 24x7 production environment.
- Pursued high quality standards and communication skills